Inventory of the Luis Kutner papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 232: 1)
  - "The Neglected Ninth Amendment: The Other Rights Retained by the People,", 1967
  - "World Habeas Corpus: The Difference between Civilization and Tyranny,", 1968
  - "World Habeas Corpus and the Rule of Law,", 1969
  - "Homo Arbiter: Emerging Judicial Man--Suggestions for Qualifications and Credentials,", 1970
  - "Plato and Aristotle: Precursors of the Human Rights of World Habeas Corpus,", 1980
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Due Process and the Judeo-Christian Tradition,", 1980
  - "Charter of the Forest: Forgotten Companion of the Magna Carta,", 1981
  - "Magna Carta: The Ignored Legacy of Anti-Semitism,", 1982
  - "The New International Covenant for Permanent Peace,", 1989
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1957-1991 and undated (Box-folder 232: 2)
  Includes letters to the Norwegian Nobel Peace Prize Committee nominating Luis Kutner for the Nobel Peace Prize, 1988
- Clippings and printed matter relating to aggression, the environment, human rights, the peace and security of mankind, the Vietnam War, and world habeas corpus, 1958-1993 (Box-folder 232: 3-6)
- Applications, draft indictment of Saddam Hussein and other Iraqi officials, and petitions, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 232: 7)
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 232: 8)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box 233)
  - "Legal Ecumenics"
    - Vols. I-IV, undated
    - Vols. I-IX, undated (Box 234)
    - Vols. X-XI, undated (Box 235)
  - "Politicide: The Necessity of an International Court of Criminal Justice,", undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Proposal for an International Court of Habeas Corpus and the United Nations Writ of Habeas Corpus,", undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus for International Man: A Credo for International Due Process of Law,", 1959
  - "The Case for an International Writ of Habeas Corpus: A Reply,", 1960
  - "Habeas Proprietatem: An International Remedy for Wrongful Seizures of Property,", 1961
  - "Due Process of Economy: A Proposal for a United States Economy Court,", 1961
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Legal Absolute for Survival,", 1962
  - "Due Process of Outer-Space Law: The International Cosmos Court--A proposal,", 1962
  - "The Improvement of the International Law-Making Process,", 1961
  - "Due Process of Economy: Antitrust Control of Labor,", 1962
  - "Crime-Torts: Due Process of Compensation for Crime Victims,", 1966
  - "Overdue Due Process for Women Lawyers,", 1968
  - "Due Process of War: An Ad Hoc War Crimes Tribunal--A Proposal,", 1968
  - "Due Process of Abortion,", 1968
  - "A World Outer Space Prison: A Proposal,", 1969
  - "Homo Arbiter: Emerging Judicial Man--Suggestions for Qualifications and Credentials,", 1970
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Ombudsman for Mankind,", 1970
  - "The Freedom of Academic Freedom: A Legal Dilemma,", 1971
  - "Symposium: Law and Social Change,", 1972
  - "Due Process for Crime Victims,", 1972
  - "Due Process of Rebellion,", 1972
  - "Constructive Notice: A Proposal to End International Terrorism,", 1973
  - "Due Process of Debate: A Senator's Dilemma,", 1974
  - "A Legal Note on the Nixon Pardon: Equal Justice Vis-à-vis Due Process,", 1975
  - "A Legal Note on the Nixon Pardon: Equal Justice Vis-à-vis Due Process,", 1975
  - "Due Process in the Contested New Hampshire Senate Election: Fact, Fiction, or Farce,", 1975
  - "The Emerging United States of Earth: World Habeas Corpus as the Ligament of Unilaw and Global Justice,", 1978
  - "Euthanasia: Due Process for Death with Dignity--The Living Will,", 1978-1979
  - "The Human Rights of Karl Marx,", 1979
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Legacy of Mount Sinai,", 1980
  - "Global Solar Treaty: Energy for Peace--A Proposal,", 1981
  - "A World Genocide Tribunal--Rampart against Future Genocide: Proposal for Planetary Preventive Measures Supplementing a Genocide Early Warning System,", 1981
  - "The Arctic Ocean: A Contest for Sovereignty,", 1983
  - "World Habeas Corpus, Human Rights and Individual Freedom: Myth, Farce and Political Reality,", 1984
  - "Habeas Proprietatem Revisited,", 1984
- Miscellany, 1954-1981
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box 236)
  - "World Habeas Corpus and International Extradition,", 1964
  - "International Due Process for Prisoners of War: The Need for a Special Tribunal of World Habeas Corpus,", 1967
  - "Habeas Scholastica: An Ombudsman for Academic Due Process--A Proposal,", 1968
  - "Habeas Marinus: A Proposal in Ocean Law,", 1969
  - "Due Process of Euthanasia: The Living Will--A Proposal,", 1969
  - "Contempt Power: The Black Robe--A Proposal for Due Process,", 1971
  - "Executive Privilege: Growth of Power over a Declining Congress,", 1973-1974
  - "Nixon V. Cox: Due Process of Executive Authority,", 1974
  - "Due Process of Foreign Policy: Proposals for Presidential Guidelines,", 1974
  - "The Genocide of Whales: A Crime against Humanity,", 1978
  - "Euthanasia: Due Process for Death with Dignity--The Living Will,", 1978-1979
  - "Soviet Jewry and World Habeas Corpus,", 1984
  - "Our Extra Constitutional Census,", 1991
- Printed matter, 1962-1989
  Relates to aggression, equity in international law, Palestinian refugees, human rights, use of force in international law, international trade, and world peace
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box 237)
  - "Minimizing Personality Tensions in Industrial Relations,", undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus for International Man: A Credo for International Due Process of Law,", 1959
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Treaty-Statute of the International Court of Habeas Corpus--A Proposal,", 1959
  - "The Case for an International Writ of Habeas Corpus: A Reply,", 1960
  - "Due Process of Economy: A Proposal for a United States Economy Court,", 1961
  - "Unfair Comment: A Warning to News Media,", 1962
  - "The Illusion of Due Process in Commitment Proceedings,", 1962
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Legal Absolute for Survival,", 1962
  - "Due Process of Outer-Space Law: The International Cosmos Court: A Proposal" (with Maxwell M. Rabb), 1962
  - "Due Process of Economy: Antitrust Control of Labor,", 1962
  - "Habeas Proprietatem: Due Process for International Investments--A Prior Consideration for Investments Abroad,", 1963
  - "The Desecration of the Ferguson Monument Trust: The Need for Watchdog Legislation,", 1963
  - "World Habeas Corpus and International Extradition,", 1964
  - "World Habeas Corpus: The Legal Ultimate for the Unity of Mankind,", 1965
  - "Charitable Trust Legislation in the Several States" (with Henry H. Koven), 1966
  - "Crime-Torts: Due Process of Compensation for Crime Victims,", 1966
  - "World Habeas Corpus: The Difference between Civilization and Tyranny,", 1966
  - "Politicide: The Necessity of an International Court of Criminal Justice,", 1972
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Legal Ligament for Political Diversity,", 1967
  - "World Habeas Corpus, Human Rights and World Community,", 1967
  - "Due Process of Family Privacy: World Civil Liberty and World Habeas Corpus,", 1967
  - "The Neglected Ninth Amendment: The Other Rights Retained by the People,", 1967
  - "Overdue Process for Women Lawyers,", 1968
  - "Due Process of War: An Ad Hoc War Crimes Tribunal--A Proposal,", 1968
  - "Habeas Marinus: Due Process of Inner Space--A Proposal,", 1968
  - "Habeas Scholastica: An Ombudsman for Academic Due Process--A Proposal,", 1968
  - "World Outer Space Prison: A Proposal,", 1969
  - "World Habeas Corpus and the Rule of Law,", 1969
  - "Habeas Marinus: A Proposal in Ocean Law,", 1969
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Ombudsman for Mankind,", 1970
  - "Due Process of Human Transplants: A proposal,", 1970
  - "Homo Arbiter: Emerging Judicial Man--Suggestions for Qualifications and Credentials,", 1970
  - "International Eminent Domain,", 1970
  - "The Freedom of Academic Freedom: A Legal Dilemma,", 1971
  - "Freedom of Information: Due Process of the Right to Know,", 1972
  - "Commentary: A trilogy on Great Philosophers and the Law,", 1972
  - "Constructive Notice: A Proposal to End International Terrorism,", 1973
  - "Executive Privilege: Growth of Power over a Declining Congress,", 1973-1974
  - "Advice and Dissent: Due Process of the Senate,", 1974
  - "Due Process of Debate: A Senator's Dilemma,", 1974
  - "The Living Will, Coping with the Historical Event of Death,", 1975
  - "The Control and Prevention of Transnational Pollution: A Case for World Habeas Ecologicus,", 1977
  - "The Emerging United States of Earth: World Habeas Corpus as the Ligament of Unilaw and Global Justice,", 1978
  - "The Genocide of Whales: A Crime against Humanity,", 1978
  - "Euthanasia: Due Process for Death with Dignity--The Living Will,", 1978-1979
  - "Global Solar Treaty: Energy for Peace--A Proposal,", 1980
  - "A World Genocide Tribunal — Rampart against Future Genocide: Proposal for Planetary Preventative Measures Supplementing a Genocide Early Warning System,", 1984
- Printed matter relating to the crime rate in the United States, freedom of choice, human rights, Kutner College, and world habeas corpus, 1954-1977
- Scrapbook--Ronald Pritikin, 1945-1990 (Box 238)
- Printed matter, including an announcement of a book by Luis Kutner and an article about him, 1965-1983
- Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 239: 1)
  Includes a letter to Boris Yeltsin
- Writings by Luis Kutner in Common Law Lawyer
  - "The Talmud and the Proposal for World Habeas Corpus in Historical Perspective,", 1980 (Box-folder 239: 2)
  - "The Roots of World Habeas Corpus,", 1980
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Legacy of Mount Sinai,", 1980
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Due Process and the Judeo-Christian Tradition,", 1980
  - "Global Solar Treaty: Energy for Peace--A Proposal,", 1981
  - "Magna Carta: The Ignored Legacy of Anti-Semitism,", 1982
  - "Outer Space Torts: International Cosmos Court--A Proposal,", 1983
  - "The Arctic Ocean: A Contest of Sovereignty,", 1983
  - World Habeas Corpus--Human Rights and Individual Freedom: Myth, Farce and Political Reality,", 1984
  - "Habeas Propietatem Revisited,", 1984
  - "Constructive Notice: A Proposal to End International Terrorism,", 1985
  - Minutes of the Meeting of the Commission for International Due Process of Law, submitted by Luis Kutner, 1986
  - "The Revolt of Planet Earth,", 1986
  - "Draft Indictment of Saddam Hussain,", 1991 (Box-folder 239: 3)
  - World Habeas Project envisioned by Luis Kutner, 1991
  - "Statute of the World Court of Human Rights,", undated (Box-folder 239: 4)
  - "Due Process of War: An Ad Hoc War Crimes Tribunal--A Proposal,", 1968
  - "Due Process of Rebellion,", 1972
  - "The Control and Prevention of Transnational Pollution: A Case for World Habeas Ecologicus,", 1977
  - "Just before the Sanhedrin,", 1991
  - "Preface to the Atomic Space Age,", undated (Folder 239: 5)
  - "World Habeas Corpus and the Sanctity of Individual Freedom,", undated (Folder 239: 6)
- Printed matter relating to Luis Kutner's fight for justice, living wills, and world habeas corpus, 1961-1986 (Folder 239: 7)
- Petitions to the United Nations, undated (Box-folder 240: 1)
  Includes a letter to Perez de Cuellar, 1991
- Correspondence, 1984-1993 (Folder 240: 2)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Folder 240: 3)
  - "Statute of the World Court of Human Rights,", undated
  - "The Revolt of Planet Earth,", 1986
- Human rights, 1978-1982 (Folder 240: 4)
  Correspondence, paper by Steven Ackerman, policy statement, report on the human rights violations in Uganda
- World habeas corpus, 1991-1992 (Folder 240: 5)
  List of projects, newsletter, and printed matter
- Miscellany, 1974, 1993 (Folder 240: 6)
  Obituary, world government identity card, and passport of Luis Kutner
- Sound recording of interview of Luis Kutner, 1966
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Use copy reference number: 82015_a_0002025
  Interview of Kutner discussing UNICEF on Jack Elgan show, Chicago, Illinois. One 1/4-inch sound tape reel
- Photographic negatives, 1960-1980 (Box-folder 241: 1-2)
- Photographs depicting Luis Kutner and family, 1960-1980 (Box-folder 241: 3)
- Photographs depicting Luis Kutner and family, 1924-1980 (Box-folder 242: 1-2)
- Correspondence, 1964-1985
  - Geni Charlesworth, 1974 (Box-folder 242: 3)
  - Edward C. Rose, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 242: 4)
- United States of America v. Jonathan J. Pollard, 1991 (Box-folder 242: 5)
- Adlai Stevenson, 1982 (Box-folder 243: 1)
- Walter Heller, 1982 (Box-folder 243: 2)
- Chicago Center for World Survival, 1982 (Box-folder 243: 3)
- Equal Rights Amendment, 1982 (Box-folder 243: 4)
- Lie detectors, 1982 (Box-folder 243: 5)
- Commission for International Due Process of Law, 1982 (Box-folder 243: 6)
- Gus Diamond, 1982 (Box-folder 243: 7)
- Correspondence, 1982-1992
  - Steven Bauman, 1982 (Box-folder 143: 8)
  - A. B. M. Badrud Doulah, 1984 (Box-folder 143: 9)
  - Aloysius A. Mazewski, 1982 (Box-folder 143: 10)
  - Paulist Press, 1982 (Box-folder 143: 11)
  - Policy Sciences Center, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 243: 12)
  - Balwant Singh, 1985 (Box-folder 243: 13)
  - Robert J. Spinazzola, 1982 (Box-folder 243: 14)
- Photographs depicting Luis Kutner and relatives, 1880-1980 (Box-folder 243: 15)
- Irish Republican Army, 1982 (Box-folder 244: 1)
- Philippines, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 244: 2)
- Nuremberg Charter, 1972 (Box-folder 244: 3)
- Correspondence, 1980-1992
  - Chicago Board of Rabbis, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 244: 4)
  - S. P. Kundra, 1982 (Box-folder 244: 5)
  - Leo Kuper, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 244: 6)
  - Thomas Slee, 1982 (Box-folder 244: 7)
  - United Irish-American Societies of Delaware Valley, Pennsylvania, 1982 (Box-folder 244: 8)
  - University of Denver Law Center (Ved P. Nanda), 1988-1992 (Box-folder 244: 9)
- Lois Frolova, 1982 (Box-folder 245: 1)
- Haiti, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 245: 2)
- Harold Lasswell, 1982 (Box-folder 245: 3)
- Yugoslavia, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 245: 4)
- Egypt, 1991 (Box-folder 245: 5)
- Ethiopia, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 245: 6)
- Correspondence, 1982-1992
  - American Bar Association, 1992 (Box-folder 245: 7)
  - Melvin Belli, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 245: 8)
  - John Paul II, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 245: 9)
  - Leota Moore, 1982-1989 (Box-folder 245: 10)
  - Maxwell M. Rabb, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 245: 11)
  - Michael Zweig, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 245: 12)
- Paper by Luis Kutner, "Habeas Foeta: Due Process for the Unborn", 1986-1987 (Box-folder 246: 1)
- Kurt Waldheim, 1988 (Box-folder 246: 2)
- Afghanistan, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 246: 3)
- Senegal, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 246: 4)
- South Africa, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 246: 5)
- Correspondence, 1986-1988
  - Perry M. Berke, 1986 (Box-folder 246: 6)
  - Maurice Lepavsky, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 286: 7)
  - Joyce Seunarine, 1986 (Box-folder 246: 8)
  - Caroline K. Simon, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 246: 9)
  - Sanford Weill, 1986 (Box-folder 246: 10)
- Raphael Gregorian, 1986 (Box-folder 247: 1)
- Nigeria, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 247: 2)
- Louis Farrakhan, 1986 (Box-folder 247: 3)
- Jim Thompson, 1983 (Box-folder 247: 4)
- Saudi Arabia, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 247: 5)
- Correspondence, 1976-1989
  - Frederick Barad, 1986 (Box-folder 247: 6)
  - Joseph Fletcher, 1985 (Box-folder 247: 7)
  - Sir Peter Hall, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 247: 8)
  - Bob Hope and Chuck Eddy, 1976-1989 (Box-folder 247: 9)
  - David Lubell, 1986 (Box-folder 247: 10)
  - Scott Meredith, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 247: 11)
  - Brian Muldoon, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 247: 12)
  - Yvonne Pugh, 1986 (Box-folder 247: 13)
  - Charles E. Rice, 1986 (Box-folder 247: 14)
  - Patrick Roche, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 247: 15)
  - Charles and Maurice Saatchi, 1986 (Box-folder 247: 16)
  - Michael Smith, 1986 (Box-folder 247: 17)
  - Douglas Warlick, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 247: 18)
- Nobel Peace Prize, 1962-1975 (Box-folder 248: 1-2)
- Biographical information about Luis Kutner, 1962-1973 (Box-folder 248: 3)
- Internet and human rights, 1979-1992 (Box-folder 248: 4)
- Living will, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 249: 1-10)
- Living will, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 250: 1-10)
- Printed matter relating to human rights issues, 1961-1975 (Box-folder 251: 1-20)
- Printed matter relating to the legal career of Luis Kutner, 1939-1983 (Box-folder 252: 1-10)
- Jacques-Yves Cousteau, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 1)
- Danny Ha, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 253: 2)
- Private prisons, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 3)
- Pornography vs. due process, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 4)
- William H. Rehnquist, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 5)
- Impeachment, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 6)
- Misprision, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 253: 7)
- United Nations, 1991 (Box-folder 253: 8)
- Correspondence, 1982-1992
  - David Berliner, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 9)
  - Roande Ibarra Cutner, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 10)
  - Doubleday & Company, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 11)
  - Bert Early, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 12)
  - Suzie Kim, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 13)
  - Bernard R. Lerner, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 14)
  - Lorimar-Telepictures, 1982-1991 (Box-folder 253: 15)
  - John Thomas Moran, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 253: 16)
  - Gordon S. Patton, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 17)
  - Ruder, Finn & Rotman, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 18)
  - Baqar H. Shah, 1986 (Box-folder 253: 19)
  - Louis T. Tenta, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 253: 20)
- Ivan Boesky, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 254: 1)
- Henrotin Hospital, 1987 (Box-folder 254: 2)
- Mikhail Gorbachev, 1986-1992 (Box-folder 254: 3)
- Adan Khashoggi, 1989 (Box-folder 254: 4)
- Correspondence, 1978-1987
  - Chris Fogarty, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 254: 5)
  - Helen Getto, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 254: 6)
  - Gideon Hausner, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 254: 7)
  - Zehara Lawenthal, 1978-1987 (Box-folder 254: 8)
- William Shakespeare, 1974-1992 (Box-folder 255: 1)
- Turkey, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 255: 2)
- Veterans, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 255: 3)
- William O. Douglas, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 255: 4)
- Senior Citizens Crime Commission, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 255: 5)
- Patents, 1987 (Box-folder 255: 6)
- Correspondence, 1986-1989
  - Terry Barnich, 1986 (Box-folder 255: 7)
  - Body Politic Theatre, 1986 (Box-folder 255: 8)
  - John Brennan, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 255: 9)
  - Arthur Cantor, 1987 (Box-folder 255: 10)
  - Sheila Formoy, 1987 (Box-folder 255: 11)
  - Naval Institute Press, 1986 (Box-folder 255: 12)
  - Larry Sales, 1988 (Box-folder 255: 13)
  - Daniel H. Weisberg, 1986 (Box-folder 255: 14)
- Second amendment, 1985 (Box-folder 256: 1)
- Raoul Wallenberg, 1975-1984 (Box-folder 256: 2)
- Raoul Wallenberg, 1973-1984 (Box-folder 257: 1-2)
- Ferdinand Marcos, 1986 (Box-folder 258: 1)
- Saddam Hussein, 1991 (Box-folder 258: 2)
- Ferdinand Marcos, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 259: 1)
- Correspondence, 1973-1993
  - Louis René Beres, 1990 (Box-folder 259: 2)
  - Roland I. Pritikin, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 259: 3)
  - Norman Kean, Bruce Becker, and Tony D'Amato, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 260: 1)
  - Joann Langston, 1987 (Box-folder 260: 2)
- Writing by Luis Kutner, "Omnicide: or Due Process of Peace", 1985
- Clippings relating to Luis Kutner, 1965-1983 (Box-folder 261: 2)
- United States of America v. Jonathan Jay Pollard, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 261: 3)
- Trademarks, 1962-1982 (Box-folder 261: 4)
- Framed letter from Roscoe Pound, 1957 (Box-folder 262: 1)
- Framed letter of appointment as honorary consul of Ecuador, 1950 (Box-folder 262: 2)
- Framed diploma from John Marshall Law School, 1970 (Box-folder 262: 4)
- Living will, 1988 (Box-folder 262: 4)
- Tibet, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 262: 5)
- Freedom of Information Act inquiries, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 263: 1)
- Mailing lists, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 263: 2)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1981-1989 (Box-folder 263: 3)
- Armenia, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 264: 1-2)
- Correspondence, 1984-1987
  - Ludmila Boreisha, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 264: 3)
  - Andrew Kopan, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 264: 4-5)
- World habeas corpus symposium, 1967 (Box-folder 265: 1)
- United States of America v. Jonathan Jay Pollard, 1991 (Box-folder 265: 2)
- Writings by Luis Kutner, 1961-1974
  - "An International Writ of Habeas Corpus: Protection of Personal Liberty in a World of Diverse Systems of Public Order", 1961 March (Box-folder 265: 3)
  - World Habeas Corpus, 1962 (Box-folder 265: 4)
  - "World Habeas Corpus-A Legal Absolute for Survival", 1962 February (Box-folder 265: 5)
  - "Due Process of Economy: Antitrust Control of Labor", 1962 October (Box-folder 265: 6)
  - I, the Lawyer (Box-folder 265: 7)
  - "Crime-torts: Due Process of Compensation for Crime Victims", 1966 April (Box-folder 265: 8)
  - "Due Process of Family Privacy: World Civil Liberty and World Habeas Corpus", 1967 June (Box-folder 265: 9)
  - "The Neglected Ninth Amendment: The 'Other Rights' Retained by the People", 1967 Fall (Box-folder 265: 10)
  - "Executive Privilege: Growth of Power over a Declining Congress", 1973-1974 (Box-folder 265: 11)
- Correspondence, 1980-1992
  - Ira B. Marshall, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 266: 1)
  - Linda Parks, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 266: 2)
  - Jerrold Wexler, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 266: 3)
- Biographical materials relating to Luis Kutner, 1959-1976 (Box-folder 267: 1)
- Moishe Tshombe case, 1967 (Box-folder 267: 2)
- Writings by Luis Kutner, 1965-1984
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Legal Ligament for Political Diversity", 1965 September 15 (Box-folder 267: 3)
  - "World Habeas Corpus, Human Rights and World Community", 1967 Autumn (Box-folder 267: 4)
  - "Due Process of Euthanasia: The Living Will, a Proposal", 1969 Summer (Box-folder 267: 5)
  - "Homo Arbiter: Emerging Judicial Man-Suggestions for Qualifications and Credentials", 1970 (Box-folder 267: 6)
  - "Due Process of Rebellion", 1972 Fall (Box-folder 267: 7)
  - "World Habeas Corpus: The Conquering March of an Idea", 1980 (Box-folder 267: 8)
  - "Global Solar Treaty: Energy for Peace, a Proposal", 1981 July/August (Box-folder 267: 9)
  - "Outer Space Torts: International Cosmos Court, a Proposal", 1983 March/April (Box-folder 267: 10)
  - "The Arctic Ocean: A Contest of Sovereignty", 1983 September/October (Box-folder 267: 11)
  - "Habeas Propietam Revisited", 1984 November/December (Box-folder 267: 12)
- Correspondence, 1973-1991
  - Ira B. Marshall, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 268: 1)
  - Jordan Paust, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 268: 2)
  - William J. Scott, 1976 (Box-folder 268: 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 268: 4)
- Namibia, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 269: 1)
- Ad hoc tribunals, 1989 (Box-folder 269: 2)
- Burundi, 1988 (Box-folder 269: 3)
- El Salvador, 1989 (Box-folder 269: 4)
- Guatemala, 1988 (Box-folder 269: 5)
- Correspondence, 1988-1991
  - Clyde O. Bowles, 1989 (Box-folder 269: 6)
  - Edgar M. Bronfman, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 269: 7)
  - Olga Cho, 1988 (Box-folder 269: 8)
  - Lynne C. Handy, 1989 (Box-folder 269: 9)
  - Leonard Horwin, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 269: 10)
  - Bill Kurtis, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 269: 11)
  - Burr McCloskey, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 269: 12)
  - Tom Pritzker, 1989
- Jonathan Jay Pollard, 1988 (Box-folder 270: 1)
- Freedom, 1977 (Box-folder 270: 2)
- World habeas corpus mailing list, 1970 (Box-folder 270: 3)
- Writings by Luis Kutner, 1966-1970
  - "American Nazi Rockwell and the Jews of Chicago", 1966 (Box-folder 270: 4)
  - "International Action Commission", 1970 (Box-folder 270: 5)
- Clippings relating to Luis Kutner, 1966-1978 (Box-folder 270: 6)
- Correspondence, 1980-1990
  - Roger Baldwin, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 270: 7)
  - Suzy Freeland-Zarkovich, 1989 (Box-folder 270: 8)
  - Arthur J. Goldberg, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 270: 9)
  - Charles Percy and Scott Cohen, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 270: 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 270: 11)
- Nobel Peace Prize nomination, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 171: 1)
- United States of America v. Anne Henderson Pollard, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 271: 2)
- Correspondence, 1983-1993
  - Institute on the Holocaust and Genocide, 1983-1993 (Box-folder 171: 4)
  - Leonard Sutton, 1990 (Box-folder 171: 4)
- Writings by Luis Kutner, 1962-1963
  - "The Illusion of Due Process in Commitment Proceedings", 1962 (Box-folder 272: 1)